<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS type="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>

<!-- /*******************************************************************************
 * Copyright (c) 2000, 2005 IBM Corporation and others.
 * All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
 * are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
 * which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
 * http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
 * 
 * Contributors:
 *     IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation
 *******************************************************************************/ -->

<contexts>
<context id="misc0170">
<description>Use this dialog to edit the Web content settings for a Web project. You can specify the default document type, CSS profile, and target device. The public ID and system ID are populated automatically. To restore the defaults, click <b>Restore Defaults</b>.
</description>
<topic label="Structured text editors for markup languages" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/csrcedt004.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="webx0030">
<description>This page lets you specify the line delimiter and the text encoding that will be used when you create, save, or load an HTML file.

Various development platforms use different line delimiters to indicate the start of a new line. Select the operating system that corresponds to your development or deployment platform.
<b>Note:</b> This delimiter will not automatically be added to any documents that currently exist. It will be added only to documents that you create after you select the line delimiter type and click <b>Apply</b>, or to existing files that you open and then resave after you select the line delimiter type and click <b>Apply</b>.

The encoding attribute is used to specify the default character encoding set that is used when either creating HTML files or loading your HTML files into the editor.  Changing the creating files encoding causes any new HTML files that are created from scratch to use the selected encoding.
</description>
<topic label="Setting preferences for structured text editors" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt025.html"/>
</context>

<context id="webx0031">
<description>This page lets you specify the formatting, content assist, and capitalization style that will be used when you edit an HTML file.

Enter a maximum width in the <b>Line width</b> field to specify the line width to break a line to fit onto more than one line when the document is formatted.

Select <b>Split multiple attributes each on a new line</b> to start every attribute on a new line when the document is formatted. Attributes will return to the same margin as the previous line.

Select <b>Indent using tabs</b> if you want to use tab characters (\t) as the standard formatting indentation.

If you prefer to use spaces, select <b>Indent using spaces</b>.

You can also specify the <b>Indentation size</b> which is the number of tabs or space characters used for formatting indentation.

Select <b>Clear all blank lines</b> to remove blank lines when the document is formatted.

To apply these formatting styles, select the <b>Format Document</b> menu item.

If the <b>Automatically make suggestions</b> check box is selected, you can specify that certain characters will cause the content assist list to pop up automatically. Specify these characters in the <b>Prompt when these characters are inserted</b> field.

Select the Uppercase or Lowercase radio button to determine the case for tag and attribute names that are inserted into the document when using content assist or code generation.
</description>
<topic label="Setting preferences for structured text editors" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt025.html"/>
</context>

<context id="webx0032">
<description>This page lets you customize the syntax highlighting that the HTML editor does when you are editing a file.

The <b>Content type</b> field contains a list of all the source types that you can select a highlighting style for. You can either select the content type that you want to work with from the drop-down list, or click text in the text sample window that corresponds to the content type for which you want to change the text highlighting.

The <b>Foreground</b> and <b>Background</b> push buttons open <b>Color</b> dialog boxes that allow you to specify text foreground and background colors, respectively. Select the <b>Bold</b> check box to make the specified content type appear in bold.

Click the <b>Restore Default</b> push button to set the highlighting styles back to their default values.
</description>
<topic label="Setting preferences for structured text editors" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt025.html"/>
</context>

<context id="webx0033">
<description>This page lets you create new and edit existing templates that will be used when you edit an HTML file.
</description>
<topic label="Adding and removing HTML templates" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt024.html"/>
<topic label="Setting preferences for structured text editors" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt025.html"/>
</context>

<context id="xmlm1100">
<description>Cleanup options enable you to update a document so that it is well-formed and formatted.

The following cleanup options let you select radio buttons to choose the type of cleanup to be performed:
- <b>Tag name case for HTML</b>: Unless set to <b>As-is</b>, changes the case of all tags in a file for easier visual parsing and consistency.
- <b>Attribute name case for HTML</b>: Unless set to <b>As-is</b>, changes the case of all attributes in a file for easier visual parsing and consistency.

The following cleanup options can be set to on or off, so that you can limit the type of cleanup performed:
- <b>Insert required attributes</b>: Inserts an missing attributes that are required by the tag to make the element or document well-formed.
- <b>Insert missing tags</b>: Completes any missing tags (such as adding an end tag) necessary to make the element or document well-formed.
- <b>Quote attribute values</b>: Appropriately adds double- or single-quotes before and after attribute values if they are missing.
- <b>Format source</b>: Formats the document just as the <b>Format Document</b> context menu option does, immediately after performing any other specified <b>Cleanup</b> options.
- <b>Convert line delimiters to</b>: Converts all line delimiters in the file to the selected operating system's type.
</description>
<topic label="Structured text editors for markup languages" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/csrcedt004.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

</contexts>
