<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS type="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>
<!-- /*******************************************************************************
 * Copyright (c) 2001, 2005 IBM Corporation and others.
 * All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
 * are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
 * which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
 * http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
 * 
 * Contributors:
 *     IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation
 *******************************************************************************/ -->
<contexts>

<context id="sted0001">
<description>This page lets you customize the appearance of the structured text editors.
When the <b>Highlight matching brackets</b> option is selected, whenever the cursor is next to a bracket or curly braces, its opening or closing counter part is highlighted.
Select the <b>Report problems as you type</b> check box to update validity annotations (temporary annotations, such as missing required attributes based on a DTD, that go away when the editor is closed, or the problem is fixed) as the user types.
In the <b>Appearance color options</b> table, you can adjust various editor appearance features.
</description>
<topic label="Setting preferences for structured text editors" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt025.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="sted0003">
<description>This page lets you customize hover text in the structured text editors.
</description>
<topic label="Setting preferences for structured text editors" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt025.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclispe.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="xmlm1010">
<description>Content assist helps you to finish tags or lines of code and insert templates. Depending on the source markup language, the choices that are available in the content assist list are based on tags defined by DTD and schema files, tag library descriptors, or content model standard that is specified for the file being edited. HTML content assist choices are based on the W3C HTML 4.01 content model.

If your cursor is in a position where content assist is available, a pop-up list of available choices is displayed. The content assist list displays all available completions for the current cursor position, including templates. Content assist is also available by pressing Ctrl+Space.
</description>
<topic label="Content assist" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/csrcedt006.html"/>
<topic label="Getting content assistance in structured text editors" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt005.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="xmlm1030">
<description>Select this option to format an entire document. Formatting restores element and attribute indentation and positioning, which may have been offset during editing, to see nesting hierarchies and relationships more clearly in the file. Edit the appropriate Preferences pages to make changes in specific formatting behavior.
</description>
<topic label="Structured text editors for markup languages" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/csrcedt004.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="xmlm1040">
<description>Select this option to format selected elements. Formatting restores element and attribute indentation and positioning, which may have been offset during editing, to see nesting hierarchies and relationships more clearly in the file.
</description>
<topic label="Structured text editors for markup languages" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/csrcedt004.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="xmlm1070">
<description>Select this option to open the <b>Properties</b> view, which displays properties relevant to the current element if any exist.
</description>
<topic label="Properties view" href="../org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/concepts/cpropview.htm"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="xmlm2000">
<description>This structured text editor lets you edit a text file that is coded in a markup language. The editor provides many text editing features, such as content assist, syntax highlighting, unlimited undo and redo, element selection and formatting, and document formatting. For a more specific list of editing features, see the first link below.
</description>
<topic label="Structured text editors for markup languages" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/csrcedt004.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>

<context id="webx0000">
<description>This page lets you customize task tag discovery in the structured text editors.
</description>
</context>

<context id="ecss0000">
<description>The CSS source page editor lets you edit a cascading style sheet. The editor provides many text editing features, such as content assist, syntax highlighting, unlimited undo and redo, element selection and formatting, and document formatting.
</description>
<topic label="Structured text editors for markup languages" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/csrcedt004.html"/>
<topic label="Editing text coded in markup languages - overview" href="../org.eclipse.wst.sse.doc.user/topics/tsrcedt000.html"/>
</context>
<context id="misc0180">
 <description>Use this dialog to edit the CSS content settings for a CSS file. You can specify CSS profile or restore the default by clicking <b>Restore Defaults</b>.
 </description>
</context>
</contexts>
