<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS type="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>

<!-- /*******************************************************************************
	* Copyright (c) 2000, 2005 IBM Corporation and others.
	* All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
	* are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
	* which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
	* http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
	* 
	* Contributors:
	*     IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation
	*******************************************************************************/ -->

<!-- plugin: org.eclipse.wst.dtd.ui -->

<contexts>
	<context id="csh_outer_container">
		<description />
	</context>
	<context id="webx0020"><!-- dtd files preference page -->
		<description>
			This page lets you choose which suffix (<b>dtd</b>, <b>ent</b>, or <b>mod</b>) is added when a new DTD file is created.
		</description>
	</context>
	<context id="webx0021"><!-- dtd styles preference page -->
		<description>
			This page lets you customize the syntax highlighting that the document type definition (DTD) editor does when you are editing a file.

			The <b>Content type</b> field contains a list of all the source types that you can select a highlighting style for. You can either select the content type that you want to work with from the drop-down list, or click text in the text sample window that corresponds to the content type for which you want to change the text highlighting.

			The <b>Foreground</b> and <b>Background</b> push buttons open <b>Color</b> dialog boxes that allow you to specify text foreground and background colors, respectively. Select the <b>Bold</b> check box to make the specified content type appear in bold.

			Click the <b>Restore Default</b> push button to set the highlighting styles back to their default values.
		</description>
		<topic
			href="../org.eclipse.wst.dtdeditor.doc.user/topics/tedtsrcst.html"
			label="Setting source highlighting styles" />
	</context>
	<context id="webx0022"><!-- dtd template preference page -->
		<description>
			Templates are a chunk of predefined code that you can insert into a DTD file when it is created.

			Click <b>New</b> if you want to create a completely new template.

			Supply a new template <b>Name</b> and <b>Description</b>. The <b>Context</b> for the template is the context in which the template is available in the proposal list when content assist is requested. Specify the <b>Pattern</b> for your template using the appropriate tags, attributes, or attribute values to be inserted by content assist.

			If you want to insert a variable, click the <b>Insert Variable</b> button and select the variable to be inserted. For example, the <b>date</b> variable indicates the current date will be inserted.

			You can edit, remove, import, or export a template by using the same Preferences page.

			If you have a template that you do not want to remove but you no longer want it to appear in the content assist list, clear its check box in the <b>Templates</b> preferences page.
		</description>
		<topic
			href="../org.eclipse.wst.dtdeditor.doc.user/topics/tdtemplt.html"
			label="Working with DTD templates" />
		<topic
			href="../org.eclipse.wst.dtdeditor.doc.user/topics/tcretdtd.html"
			label="Creating DTD files" />
	</context>
	<context id=""><!-- create dtd page 1 has no id atm -->
		<description>
			In the <b>File name</b> field, type the name of the DTD. The name of your DTD file must end with the extension .dtd
		</description>
		<topic
			href="../org.eclipse.wst.dtdeditor.doc.user/topics/tcretdtd.html"
			label="" />
	</context>
	<context id="dtdw0010"><!-- dtd new file wizard page 2, page 1 has no ID -->
		<description>
			Click the <b>Use DTD Template</b> check box if you want to use a DTD template as the initial content in your new DTD page. A list of available DTD templates is listed - select the one you want to use. A preview of your DTD file is shown once you select a DTD template.
		</description>
		<topic
			href="../org.eclipse.wst.dtdeditor.doc.user/topics/tdtemplt.html"
			label="Working with DTD templates" />
		<topic
			href="../org.eclipse.wst.dtdeditor.doc.user/topics/tcretdtd.html"
			label="Creating DTD files" />
	</context>
</contexts>
