<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?NLS type="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>
<!-- /*******************************************************************************
 * Copyright (c) 2000, 2006 IBM Corporation and others.
 * All rights reserved. This program and the accompanying materials
 * are made available under the terms of the Eclipse Public License v1.0
 * which accompanies this distribution, and is available at
 * http://www.eclipse.org/legal/epl-v10.html
 * 
 * Contributors:
 *     IBM Corporation - initial API and implementation
 *******************************************************************************/ -->
<contexts>
<context id="webw2000">
<description> Use this page to name your Web project and specify the file system location (the place where the resources you create are stored.) When the Use default check box is selected, the project will be created in the file system location where your workspace resides. To change the default file system location, clear the checkbox and locate the path using the <b>Browse</b> button. To configure additional options, select the <b>Next</b> button.
In the Target Runtime field, select the server where you want to publish the Web project. if a server is not already defined, click <b>New</b> to select a server runtime environment. </description>
<topic label="Creating a static Web project" href="../org.eclipse.wst.webtools.doc.user/topics/twcresta.html"/>
</context>

<context id="webw2100">
<description>Presets are used to define a default set of facet versions that will configure a project for a particular type of development. The Static Web Module facet enables the project to be deployed as a static
Web module. Click Show Runtimes to view the available runtimes and runtime compositions.</description>
<topic label="Creating a static Web project" href="../org.eclipse.wst.webtools.doc.user/topics/twcresta.html"/>
</context>

<context id="webw2200">
<description>The Web content folder is where the elements of your Web site such as Web pages, graphics and style sheets are stored. This directory structure is necessary to ensure that the content of your Web site will be included in the WAR file at deployment and that link validation will work correctly.
</description>
<topic label="Creating a static Web project" href="../org.eclipse.wst.webtools.doc.user/topics/twcresta.html"/>
</context>


</contexts>
