<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
          "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
	<?dbhtml filename="launching/launching.html" ?>
	<title>XSL Launching and Debugging</title>
	<para> XSL Tools adds support for XSL Launch and Debugging
		configurations. These allow you to setup XSL configurations for
		various jobs, and to also debug xsl stylsheet transformations.</para>
	<section
		id="XSLLaunch">
		<?dbhtml filename="launching/launching.html" ?>
		<title>XSL Launching</title>
		<para>
			In the Project Explorer, simply select the input XML file and the
			stylesheet(s) to transform it, and then right-click and select
			<emphasis>Run As > XSL Transformation</emphasis>
			.
		</para>
		<figure
			id="fig_XSLRun">
			<title>XSLT Run/Debug</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata
						align="center"
						format="PNG"
						fileref="../images/launching/launchShortct.png" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<note>
			<title>Selecting only the XSL Stylesheet</title>
			<para>
				If only the XSL Stylesheet is selected then a dialog box will prompt you for the input file to use.
			</para>
		</note>
		<para>
			Launch can also be done through the Launch Configurations pages that are used for both debugging and normal transformations.
			These configurations can be accessed through <emphasis>Run->Run Configurations</emphasis> menu bar option.
		</para>
		<section
			id="XSLLaunchConfig">
			<title>Launch Configuration</title>
			<para>
				Currently, XSL Tools only supports the launching of java based
				processors through the Run and Debug framework. To this point, it
				leverages and extends some of the support provided by the Java
				launch configurations. XSL Tools does add it's own specific features
				for launching.
			</para>
			<figure
				id="fig_XSLLaunchConfig">
				<title>Java XSLT Launch Configuration</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							align="center"
							format="PNG"
							fileref="../images/launching/XSLRunDebugConfigurations.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>
				The tabs Main, Output, and Processor control specifics for the XSLT processor and files to be run through
				the transformation.
			</para>
			<note>
				<title>XSLT Extensions</title>
				<para>If the transformation needs or makes use of extension
					functions then those jar files should be added to the Classpath tab
					so that they are picked up during the transformation. Otherwise the
					transformation will fail.</para>
			</note>
			<section id="XSLLaunch_Main">
				<title>Main Tab</title>
				<para>
					As shown in <xref linkend="fig_XSLLaunchConfig"/>, the Main Tab is where the input XML file is specified.  If a particular
					XML file is not shown in the available list when browsing the Workspace, make sure that it is added to under the XML Content
					Type in the General preference page.  Standard eclipse launching variables can be used to specify the location of the input file.
				</para>
				<para>
					A run configuration can also use a simple pipeline transformation.  Meaning that the output from one stylesheet is used as input
					to the next stylesheet.   The Stylesheet input box can have one to many stylesheets specified.  At least one stylesheet is required
					for a transformation.
				</para>
				<para>
					The last optional item are parameters.   Stylesheets can have parameters passed into them to setup configuration information.  An
					example would be the numerous parameters that can be set for a DocBook stylesheet transformation.   If the parameters are not
					specified the defaults that are defined in the stylesheet will take precedence. 
				</para>
			</section>
			<section id="XSLLaunch_Output">
				<title>Output Tab</title>
				<para>
					The Output Tab allows the specification of where the transformation should store the information.
					This can be relative to the workspace or a physical location outside the workspace.
				</para>
			<figure
				id="fig_XSLOutputTab">
				<title>Java XSLT Launch Configuration</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							align="center"
							format="PNG"
							fileref="../images/launching/XSLOutputTab.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
				
			</section>
			<section id="XSLLaunch_Processor">
				<title>Processor Tab</title>
				<para>
					The particular XSLT processor that will be used can be choosen from this tab. The
					default is to use the system default processor or what ever processor you have
					set as the default processor in the preference pages.
				</para>
				<figure
					id="fig_XSLProcessorTab">
					<title>Java XSLT Launch Configuration</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata
								align="center"
								format="PNG"
								fileref="../images/launching/XSLProcessorTab.png" />
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
				
				<note>
					<title>XSLT Debugging</title>
					<para>
						If you are setting up a launch configuration for debugging, do not choose
						the JRE Default processor, you should choose either Xalan or another adopters
						processor that supports debugging.
					</para>
				</note>
				<para>
					In addition, every processor has their own configuration options that can be specified.
					This controls such items as indentation, handling of white space, etc.  Refer to your
					processors documentation for the specific options available.
				</para>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section
		id="XSLDebug">
	    <?dbhtml filename="launching/debugging.html" ?>
		<title>XSLT Debugging</title>
		<para> XSL Tools provides a framework for XSLT processors to provide
			debugging support. The support provided is highly dependent on the
			processors. XSL Tools comes with built in support for the Xalan 2.7.1
			processor. Debugging is only available for those processors that
			support the feature and plug into the extension point. The XSL Tools
			debugger leverages the existing eclipse platform Debug View</para>
		<figure id="fig_XSLDebug">
			<title>XSLT Debugging</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							align="center"
							format="PNG"
							fileref="../images/launching/XSLDebugging.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			How the debugger acts will depend on the processor being used. Not
			all XSLT processors pass the same type of information to the
			debugger. These differences will be noted in the
			<xref
				linkend="XSLDebugProcessorSpecific" />
			section.
		</para>
		<section
			id="DebugGettingStarted">
			<?dbhtml filename="launching/debugging_gettingStarted.html" ?>
			<title>Starting a Debug Session</title>
			<para> Debugging is started the same way as launching an XSL
				Tranformation is done. Except that the debug configuration is used
				instead of the normal launch configuration. If a debugging session
				is started on a processor that does not support debugging, a dialog
				will ask if you want to switch to one of the supported debuggers.
			</para>
			<note>
				<title>Default JRE</title>
				<para> The default JRE does not have built in support for debugging,
					even though it is based on Apache Xalan. It is recommended to use
					Xalan or another processor provided by an adopter to do your
					transformations. The default processor is known to have some issues
					that Xalan and other processors do not have.</para>
			</note>
		</section>
		<section
			id="XSLDebugCommon">
		<?dbhtml filename="launching/debugging_common.html" ?>
			<title>Common Debugging Operations</title>
			<para>
				XSLT debugging is handled by the eclipse platforms debugging
				framework support as outlined in the
				<ulink
					url="/help/topic/org.eclipse.platform.doc.isv/guide/debug_debug.htm">"Program Debug and Launch Support"</ulink>
				. Common operations like stepping into (F5), stepping over (F6),
				pausing, running to a breakpoint, and relaunching are supported. In
				addition to the standard Variable and Breakpoint views provided by
				the platform, there are some XSLT specific views and functionality
				as well. All of these are common regardless of the particular XSLT
				debugger being used.
			</para>
			<tip>
				<title>Introduction to Eclipse Debugging</title>
				<para>
					<ulink
						url="http://www.mcs.vuw.ac.nz/courses/COMP205/2007T1/tools/eclipse/debugging/basics.shtml">Basic Debugging in Eclipse</ulink>
					contains a good general introduction to the basic features provided
					by the Eclipse Debug view. XSL Tools leverages many of these
					features and the same concepts apply to the XSL Tools debugger.
				</para>
			</tip>
			<para> In addition to the standard features and functionality, the
				XSL Tools debugging support adds the following additional items:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para> Result View</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>XSLT specific Variables</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>XSLT Processor Specific Functionality</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<section
				id="XSLDebugResultView">
			<?dbhtml filename="launching/debugging_resultview.html" ?>
				<title>Result View</title>
				<para> The XSLT Debugger has a result view. This will show the
					output that the stylesheet has generated to the current break point
					or since the last step command was issued.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							align="center"
							format="PNG"
							fileref="../images/launching/resultView.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<para> The result view is updated throughout the debugging process,
					and is useful to help see what output is generated at specific
					points during a transformation.</para>
			</section>
			<section
				id="XSLDebugVariables">
			<?dbhtml filename="launching/debugging_variablesview.html" ?>
				<title>Variables View</title>
				<para> The variables view will show all the local and global
					variables and params that are currently in scope. There are two
					types of variables that can be views.</para>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							align="center"
							format="PNG"
							fileref="../images/launching/nodesetVariable.png" />
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
				<itemizedlist>
					<title>Variable Types</title>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>String</emphasis>
							- These contain text values. This could be strings of text,
							numbers, or other characters.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>Nodesets</emphasis>
							- Nodesets are represented in the variables view as expandable
							variables. They contain sequences of nodes. The type of nodes are
							represented by icons for elements, attributes, text, comments or
							processing instructions.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
				<note>
					<title>Can I change the value of variables?</title>
					<para> Currently the XSLT Debugger does not support changing the
						values or contents of a variable. All XSLT variables are read
						only.</para>
				</note>
			</section>
		</section>
		<section
			id="XSLDebugProcessorSpecific">
			<?dbhtml filename="launching/debugging_processors.html" ?>
			<title>XSLT Processor Specific Support</title>
			<para> Various XSLT processors provide various levels of debugging
				support. Many do not provide support for debugging of stylesheets,
				and thus can't be used for debugging. XSL Tools provides basic
				support for Xalan, and can be used as a guide for adopters on how to
				implement their own specific debugging support for other processors.
			</para>
			<section
				id="XSLDebugXalan">
				<title>XSL Debugging with Xalan</title>
				<para> Xalan provides general stylesheet execution and evalation
					functionality. However there are a few things that Xalan does not
					suppor that other processors do.</para>
				<orderedlist>
					<title>Xalan Debugging Issues</title>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>Breakpoints</emphasis>
							- Xalan does not support stopping at Global Variables or
							Parameters when a debugging session is started. It will
							automatically start at the first template. Break points must be
							placed in templates to be honored. The reason for this is that
							Xalan lazily initializes the variables only when they are first
							used.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>XSLT Text elements</emphasis>
							- Xalan does not send notifications of xsl:text elements. These
							are skipped over when debugging.
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							<emphasis>Built In Templates</emphasis>
							- Xalan does provide notification when the built in templates are
							called, but currently the debugger does not support or display
							stepping into these templates.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</orderedlist>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>